艺彬，醒醒！
Yae-bin, wake up!
该准备上学了
It's time to get ready.
你打开新闻了吗？
Can you get the news?
你们应该去医院看看姥姥
You guys should go see grandma in hospital.
我好了
I'm done.
你难道不能吃完吗？
Aren't you going to finish?
你听我说话了吗？
Did you hear me?
为什么你不给你和你母亲买个手包呢？
Why don't you buy handbags for you and your mother?
你也想要个？
You want one too?
爱你，爸爸
Love you, Dad.
至少打个电话给姥姥
Call your grandma, at least.
这的粘稠的东西对你丈夫非常有好处……
This slimy thing here is very good for your husband...
一个高中女生遭遇了场可怕的事故……
A terrible incident happened to a high school girl...
-你好 -嗨
- Hello. - Hi.
-给你 -哦，别……
- Here. - Oh, don't...
-没什么 -谢谢你
- It's nothing. - Thank you.
你为什么勾引我？因为我是老板的女儿吗？
Why did you tempt me? Because I'm the boss's daughter?
我当然喜欢了
Of course I love it.
那可是香奈儿
It's Chanel.
别担心，回去工作吧
Don't worry. Go back to work.
嗨，嗨！
Hey, hey!
我女婿买给我
My son-in-law bought me
香奈儿！
Chanel!
我猜收购公司不是简单的事
I guess buying out companies is not easy.
谁知道你丈夫会是这么成功！
Who knew your husband would be so successful!
而你兄弟却一般般
And how your brother would turn out.
上大学时，他还搞工会的事，净扯淡
In college he was all labor union, blah blah blah-
人生很讽刺
Life is ironic.
现在词语华丽了？
Using fancy words now?
可能是我正在变成首尔人吧
Guess I'm becoming a Seoulite.
请别说他们是兄妹
Please don't say they're siblings.
我们是兄妹
We're siblings.
-什么？不可能 -没道理
- What? No way. - It doesn't make sense.
看到没？我告诉过你们！
See? I told you!
谢谢你
Thank you.
-从什么时间开始的？ -她早上很好
- When did this start? - She was OK this morning.
再忍一下！
Hang on a sec!
夏春花
HA CHUN-HWA
-你需要钱吗？ -为什么你在这？
- Do you need money? - Why are you there?
-爸爸今早上给你了 -你为什么在这？
- Dad gave you this morning. - Why are you there?
如果你需要钱，要就是了，别那样偷偷摸摸的
If you need money, just ask. Don't sneak like that.
谁说我偷偷摸摸的了？我以为你在睡觉！
Who says I'm sneaking? I thought you were sleeping!
有什么不对吗？
Is something wrong?
我认为它是本真的书！
I thought it was a real book!
有什么不对吗？
Is there something wrong?
你是唯一的
You're the only one.
在那个年纪，一切都是混乱的、激情而为的事情
At that age, everything's turmoil and a passionate encounter.
她不得不顾感情，不牺牲一切，因为
She has to sacrifice everything despite her feelings because
她是个母亲
she's a mother.
那只是个连续剧而已
It's just a drama.
你认为你是毫无波折地长大成人的吗？
You think you grew up without any troubles?
我可不怎么惹麻烦
I wasn't a big troublemaker.
不，你是，你是个大惹事鬼
No you weren't. You were a huge troublemaker.
他们不会杀了她，是不是？
They're not gonna kill her, are they?
我只有一个月的时间了
I only have a month.
-什么事呀？ -我就知道！我就知道！
- What the hell? - I knew it! I knew it!
有人在吗？
Is someone there?
没人吗？
No one?
我正在看着你呢
I'm just looking at you.
我正在
I'm just
观察你
watching you.
医生们说什么？
What do doctors say?
或许两个月多点……？
Maybe two more months...?
很疼吗？
Does it hurt a lot?
嗯……
Well...
就像成千上万的针
it's like thousands of needles...
刺你
drilling you
同时呀
at the same time.
任娜美！
IM Na-mi!
你为什么还是如此美丽？
Why are you still so pretty?
夏春花！
HA Chun-hwa!
你也不像个癌症病人那么糟
You're not bad either for a cancer patient.
你好？
Hello?
明天？
Tomorrow?
多长时间？
For how long?
两个月？
Two months?
好的
Alright.
我老公要出差
My husband is going on a business trip.
你该走了
You should go.
我会经常来的，你需要帮什么忙吗？
I'll visit often. Do you need any help?
别担心了
Don't worry.
我想起了些事情！
I thought of something!
告诉我
Tell me.
我想她们了
I miss them.
谁？
Who?
阳光姐妹
Sunny.
我想在死前看看她们
I want to see them before I die.
你什么时间做的体检？
When did you get your checkup?
前几天……
The other day...
你叔叔是不是死于癌症？
Didn't your uncle die of cancer?
或者是他老婆？
Or was it his wife?
你接到保险推销电话了吗？
Did you get an insurance sales call?
在医院碰到了一个老朋友
Bumped into an old friend at the hospital.
晚期肺癌
Late-stage lung cancer.
你有个老朋友？
You have an old friend?
高中的
From high school.
我难道没告诉你我入过小团体吗？
Didn't I tell you that I belonged to a clique?
亲爱的
Honey.
娜美
Na-mi.
啥事！
What!
我们应该再要个孩子吗？
Shall we try for another baby?
我已经绝经了
My period has stopped.
每天吃药，注意身体
Take your pills everyday and be careful.
艺彬有了，这是你的
Yae-bin has hers. This is yours.
我有钱
I have money.
和你朋友多待会，她没剩多少时间了
Spend some time with your friend. She doesn't have much left.
我得辅导艺彬考试
I have to help Yae-bin with her exams.
保重
Take care.
保重，先生！
Take care, sir!
这个点市中心通常是最好走的
Downtown is usually the best route around now.
但今天……
But today...
别加塞，笨蛋！
Stop cutting in, you fool!
冯先生？
Mr. Bong?
对不起
Sorry.
搞什……？
What the...?
对不起
I'm sorry.
屁股想挨踢吗？
Wanna get your ass kicked?
滚开
Piss off.
嗨，姐妹们，苏米来了！
Hey guys, Su-mi's here!
预备！
Attention!
鞠躬
Bow.
早上好，老师？
Good morning, teacher?
那是谁的位子？
Whose seat is that?
春花去厕所了
Chun-hwa went to the toilet.
江美，睡觉时别说话
Jang-mi, please don't talk while sleeping.
你吓着我孩子了
You're scaring my baby.
我没睡觉
I'm not sleeping.
那么，你是还在鞠躬吗？
Are you still bowing, then?
这是新转来的学生，任……
This is a new transfer student, IM...
娜美，她来自全罗道宝城郡
Na-mi. She's from Beolgyo, Jeolla-do.
这是她第一次来首尔，对她好点
It's her first time in Seoul. So be nice to her.
-好吗，江美？ -好的
- Okay, Jang-mi? - Yep.
自我介绍一下
Introduce yourself.
很高兴见到那们大家
It's nice to meet y'all.
你们
You.
我是任娜美，来自新宝城郡高中
I'm IM Na-mi from New Beolgyo High.
去坐在那边
Go sit over there.
我们来看看……
Let's see...
本月的标语是“反共产主义”
The slogan of the month is "anti-communism".
在女子高中为什么会有烟头呢？
And why are there cigarette butts in girl's high school?
如果抽烟，你们就生不了漂亮的孩子
You can't make pretty babies if you smoke.
我相信在我们班没人抽烟
I trust we don't have smokers in out class.
预备！
Attention!
鞠躬
Bow.
谢谢，老师
Thank you, teacher.
嗨，你们大家！
Hey, y'all!
宝城郡在哪？哦，产曲奇的地方吗？
Where's Beolgyo? Oh, the place with cookies?
让我看看，你带曲奇当午饭了吗？
Let me see. Did you bring cookies for lunch?
我没带午饭
I didn't bring lunch.
让她歇会
Give her a break.
嗨，你和那边的姑娘换个位子
Hey, change your seat with that girl over there.
她闻起来像月经
She smells like menstruation.
老师让我坐在这的
Teacher told me to sit here.
听话，否则你会后悔的
Listen or you'll regret.
嗨
Hey.
迷糊了吧
Get lost.
-今天你很够胆呀 -我一直胆子大
- You're gutsy today. - I always had big guts.
嗨，冷静点，姐妹
Hey, chill out guys.
你难道不走吗？有些选择是很重要……
Aren't you going? Some choices are important...
-妈的！ -现在把你的屁股挪开
- What the f--! - Get your ass off now!
对不起
I'm sorry.
这是谁？
Who's this?
新来的
New kid.
-她从哪来？ -宝城郡
- Where's she from? - Beolgyo.
曲奇之乡，她没带午饭
The town of cockies. She didn't bring lunch.
-她叫什么名字？ -任娜美
- What's her name? - IM Na-mi.
-娜美？就像那个歌手？ -对
- Na-mi? Just like the singer? - Yep.
我是春花，和那个歌手同名，夏春花
I'm Chun-hwa. Just like the singer, HA Chun-hwa.
-很高兴见到你，娜美 -我也很高兴见到你
- Nice to meet you, Na-mi. - Nice to meet ya too!
我看起来怪吗？
Do I look weird?
哦，是怪了
Ok. it's weird.
别看了
Stop staring.
我们吃饭去！
Let's go eat!
欢乐午餐时光，姐妹们！我是金DJ
Happy lunch time, Jinduk! I'm your DJ KIM,
让完美的歌曲助你消化
with perfect songs to assist your digestion.
第一首歌来自辛迪.劳帕
The first song is by Cyndi Lauper.
寻乐女孩
Girls Just Want to Have Fun.
嗨，“歌星”朋友，我们去吃午饭吧
Hey "singer" buddy, let's go have lunch.
你又要吃饭了，胖家伙？
You're eating again, fatso?
只是点面包
Just a bun.
那是谁？
Who's that?
新来的，娜美，这位是黄珍熙
New kid, Na-mi. This is HWANG Jin-hee.
她爸爸是韩国文学教授，但她主修骂人
Her dad's a Korean Lit. prof, but she majors in swearwords.
婊子在满嘴喷屎
Bitch's sayin' shit.
-你来自哪里？ -全罗道宝城郡
- Where you from? - Beolgyo, Jeolla-do.
那的人真的很爱说脏话吗？
Do people there really swear a lot?
为什么，你想去学习吗？
Why, you wanna go study?
-没错 -再见
- Yup. - Bye.
嗨，金玉！再来四个沙拉面包！
Hey, Geum-ok! Four more salad buns!
好的，再来四个！
Ok, four more!
金玉是徐医生唯一的孩子
Geum-ok is the only child of Dentist Seo.
她是个“大棒”书虫
She's a bookworm with a "big stick."
什么是“大棒”？
What's a "big stick"?
让愤怒发泄出来有利健康
It's healthy to let out anger.
春花！
Chun-hwa!
看看那个，会走路的卷毛狗
Look at that. A walking poodle.
我们走吧
Let's go.
你使了都少瓶烫发液？
How many bottles of perm lotion did you use?
我猜你不想要双眼皮贴了？
Guess you don't want double eyelid tapes?
你很漂亮！
You're so pretty!
你是新来的吗？很高兴见到你！
Are you new? Nice to meet you!
我是未来的韩国小姐
I'm the future Miss Korea.
去读书吧，傻瓜
Go read a book, airhead.
-别再当婊子了 -管他呢
- Stop being bitchy. - Whatever.
当你成了韩国小姐，我在你的美发厅做双眼皮，嗯？
When you're a Miss Korea, double eyelids at your salon, huh?
当然可以
Of course.
那个秀智婊子去哪了？
Where's that Su-ji bitch?
抽烟刺激食欲去了
Smoking for diet.
这个
This.
记得我们班的那个漂亮女孩吗？
Remember the pretty girl in our class?
-她也是我们一伙的 -沙拉面包来了
- She's our possy, too. - Salad buns are here!
耶！
Yeah!
那个带子是怎么回事？
What's up with that ribbon?
你是新来的？嗨，我是金玉
Are you the new kid? Hi, I'm Geum-ok.
哇，那是什么鞋？
Wow, what are those shoes?
-那是“斯派斯”！ -什么“斯派斯”？
- They're "Specs"! - What's "Specs"'?
为什么我女儿这么安静？
Why's my daughter so quiet?
多谢爸爸的老板，你才去了好学校
You're in good school thanks to dad's boss.
你交到许多朋友了吗？
Did you make many pals?
别和我说话，我不说方言
Stop talkin' to me. I needn't use the dialect.
你没说方言，你听起来就像首尔的孩子
You don't use dialect. You sound like a Seoul kid.
妈妈，没人穿“斯派斯”，大家只穿耐克或者专业斯派斯
Mom, nobody wears "Specs". Only Nike or Pro-specs.
还有约达西牛仔裤……
And Jordache jeans...
你知道大家得在工厂工作多少小时
You know how many hours some kids have to work in factories
才买得起一双鞋？
to buy a pair of shoes?
她当然不知道
Of course she doesn't know.
那就是问题，妈
That's the problem, Ma.
作为新的统治阶级，我们工人需要站起来
As the new ruling class, we workers need to stand up
反抗法西斯统治和美国资本家
against the Fascist hegemony, and the Yankee capitalist.
爸爸，你必须停止像个奴隶似的为独裁者工作
Dad, you need to stop workin' for the dictator like a slave.
奴隶？
Slave?
雇员
Employee.
你混蛋
You asshole.
如果你不想要我的，你自己赚钱去
Make your own money if you don't want mine.
但如果你想要我的钱
But if you want my money,
那就闭嘴，好好上学去
shut up and just go to school.
别干傻事
Don't do anything stupid.
-爸爸！ -闭嘴！
- Dad! - Shut up.
生命是短暂的，但革命是长存的
Life is short and revolution ls forever.
妈了个傻逼！谁说生命短暂？
Fuckin' sap sucker! Who's sayin' life's short?
操他妈的满嘴狗屎的烂嘴
Fuck that filthy mouth filled with whistledickin' shit.
别怪玩这场游戏的婊子
No blamin' the bitches for playin' the game.
那没什么，十八岁时你们都要生孩子
It doesn't matter. Y'all's gotta make babes when y'all's 18.
妹妹，再给我点汤
Sis, give me more soup.
值日生？
Duty student?
读一下
Read it.
-请原谅…… -完事后你可以去厕所
- Excuse me... - You can go to the toilet after.
我认为总是叫值日生不公平
I think it's unfair to always pick on the duty student.
好的，坐下
Okay. Sit.
那么十二号值日生怎么样？
Then how about student #12?
我认为你的双眼皮不公平
I think your double eyelids are unfair.
对我的孩子不好
It's not good for my baby.
坐下
Sit.
娜美
Na-mi.
烛光可亲
Deung Hwa Ga Chin.
边上有烛光，那很好
It's good to have a candlelight near
它意味着是学习的好时间
It means good time to study.
娜美，你在原来的学校是尖子生
Na-mi, you were a top student in your old school.
在艺术竞赛中，得过许多奖
And won many awards in art contests.
安静！
Be quiet!
你想去艺术学校吗？
Do you want to go to an art school?
我不知道
I'm not sure.
下课后，来拿张艺术竞赛申请表
Come and get the art contest application form after class.
好的
Okay.
江美也应该来
Jang-mi should come too.
我会给你做个三眼皮
I'll make you triple eyelids.
夫人？
Ma'am?
你怎么能不变老呢？
How come you didn't age?
你整形了吗？
Did you get a plastic surgery?
你看起来也一样
You look the same too.
下个月我就要当姥姥了
I'm going to be a grandma next month.
未婚先孕，这是新趋势
Got pregnant before marriage. It's a new trend.
嗨，过这里来，你整眼睛了！
Hey, you come here. You changed your eyes!
让我瞧瞧，闭上眼睛
Let me see. Close your eyes.
看起来很好，好了
They look nice. Go on.
-谢谢你 -啊，好的
- Thank you. - Ah, right.
江美也来过
Jang-mi also came to visit.
她留了张她的名片给我……
She left her name card with me...
友利人寿
WOORI LIFE INSURANCE
看看这个
Look at this.
看起来不错，嗯？
Looks good, huh?
郭女士，比上月好很多
Mrs. Kwak, much better than the last month.
金女士，你需要更加努力
And Mrs. Kim, you need to try harder than this.
大家鼓掌，苏女士是本月的销售女皇
Everybody applause. Mrs. Koh is the sales queen of the month!
金女士……
Mrs. Kim...
-金江美女士？ -对
- Mrs. Kim Jang-mi? - Yes.
-你知道我要说什么 -是的
- You know what I'll say. - Yes.
更努力点
Try harder.
我会的
I will.
你把太多的精力用到你到眼皮上了
You put too much effort into your eyelids.
那样说我不公平
It's unfair to pick on me like that.
我认为这才是不公平
I think this is unfair.
别笑了，这不好笑
Stop laughing. This isn't funny.
下一位是……
Next is Mrs...
我是金江美
This is KIM Jang-mi speaking.
二十五年没见你，你就要死了
Haven't seen you for 25 years and you're already dying.
你个婊子
You bitch.
你有人寿保险吗？
Do you have life insurance?
谁能想到我成了卖保险的了？
Who would've guessed that I'd end up selling insurance?
我老公做生意把我们所有的钱都赔了
My husband lost all our money on business.
你离婚是好事
Good thing you got divorced.
但是，他怎么不来呢？你老公
Still, how can he not show up? Your husband.
没有孩子，我们就如同陌生人一样
With no kids, we're as good as strangers.
但是你难道不孤单吗？
Aren't you lonely, though?
我完全沉迷于工作
I was completely consumed with work.
现在回头看看，我猜我的确如此
Now I look back, I guess I was.
嗨，保险女，难道没有帅哥给我吗？
Hey, insurance lady, don't have a hot guy for me?
在死之前，我还能做些火热的爱
I could use some scorching love affair before I pass.
我满载而终，也不是件坏事，嗯？
I'm loaded and terminal. Not a bad deal, huh?
以牙还牙，婊子！
Right back atcha, bitch!
咱们找到她们，春花承担费用
Let's find them. Chun-hwa's paying for the fee.
难道你不想念她们吗？
Don't you miss them?
我得照顾我的家庭
I need to take care of my family.
什么，他们不能照顾自己吗？
What, they can't take care of themselves?
别烦了，我自己会找到她们
Don't bother. I'll find them alone.
怎么找？
How?
要花大约一个月的时间
It takes about a month to find
去找四个人，无论她们住在哪里
four people, no matter where they live.
你已经知道价钱
And you already know the price.
我老婆把我的衬衣弄缩水了
My wife shrunk my shirt.
我们也收信用卡……
We also accept credit cards...
抱歉
Excuse me.
我叫你待在里边的！
I told you to stay inside!
他找到了我和我丈夫
He found me and my husband
那时我们在躲债
when we were hiding from our creditors.
哦，那记忆……
Oh, the memories...
你喜欢那样？
You like that?
不管怎么说，他擅长找人
Anyway, he's good at finding people.
有些表演是必须的，那是为了让它看起来
Some acting's necessary in order to make it look
更“自然”，因为……
more "natural" because...
抱歉
Excuse me.
那么，这也是计划的表演？
So that was planned acting too?
在后边
That's on the back.
-你为什么不叫醒我？！ -吃了这个，就一口
- Why didn't you wake me'?! - Eat this. One bite.
袜子！
Socks!
我叫醒你时就起床！给
Get up when I wake you! Here.
你为什么不把内裤也给我？
Why don't you give me panties too?
你已经低血糖了，你得吃点，娜美！
You've got diabetes. You gotta eat, Na-mi!
我知道！你为什么不叫醒我？
I know! Why didn't you wake me up?
别给她吃
Don't feed her.
革命者还在监狱里挨饿呢
The revolutionaries are starving in jail.
闭嘴，你才是那个正在吃东西的人
Shut up. You're the one who's eating.
操！我不想吃
Fuck! I don't want to eat.
妈妈，成熟点！
Mom, grow up!
-我的夹克在哪？ -洗衣房！
- Where's my jacket? - Laundry!
哦，该死
Oh gosh.
让开，爸爸！
Move Dad!
她又迟到了
She's late again.
嗯，看起来很好
Yum, that looks good.
我的工具包在哪？
Where's my tool bag?
我迟到了！
I'm late!
工具包
TOOL BAG
学学这个，准备考试
Study this for your exam.
今天就到此结束
We're done for the day.
你们的老师今天生孩子
Your teacher's having a baby today.
安全过周末，别玩得太猛了
Have a safe weekend. Don't play too hard.
好的
Okay.
谢谢你，江美
Thank you, Jang-mi.
这一天总算来了！
The day has come!
你们都带“工具”了吗？
You guys all brought "tools"'?
我只带了这个
I only brought this.
你就用那个打架吧，疯子
You go fight with that, crazy.
你到底在干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
对不起，我也忘了
Sorry. I forgot, too.
该死，这可不妙
Shit, this isn't good.
我们需要七个人和她们七个打吗？
Do we need seven of us to fight with seven of them?
她们把名字改的更恶心了
They changed their name to a suckier one.
-咱们先改！ -好，好！啥名字？
- Let's get changed first! - Okay, okay! What's that?
-这是不是太可爱了？ -哦，老天，这很完美！
- Isn't this so pretty? - Oh my god, that's perfect!
为什么我们带她？
Why are we taking her?
只是为了让她们知道我们也是七个
Just to show them we also have seven.
通常我们不是真打，但你可以藏在后边
We usually don't fight for real but you can hide at the back.
我们真打吧！我们有许多工具！
Let's fight for real! We have many tools!
你有什么吃的吗？
Do you have anything to eat?
真没有
Not really.
嗨，我看起来像你的流动午餐盒吗？
Hey, do I look like a walking lunch box to you?
没还鞋，可别走，夫人
Don't go without returning your shoes, ma'am.
操，她们已经在这了
Fuck. They're already here.
女孩时代！
Girls' Generation!
夏春花
HA Chun-hwa.
为什么我们非得像塞伦盖蒂的老虎一样打架？
Why do we have to fight like the tigers of Serengeti?
要学会分享
Learn to share.
在你们停止从我们伙伴那偷窃前，不行
Not before you stop stealing from our kids.
另外，是狮子，不是老虎，笨蛋
Besides it's lions, not tigers, you idiot.
在塞伦盖蒂一定有老虎
There must be some tigers in Serengeti.
那是谁？
Who's that?
你带个小孩来吓唬我们？
You brought a kid to scare us?
看起来她想尿尿！
Looks like she wants to pee!
我不想带她，但是……
I wasn't gonna bring her, but...
你听说过“摄魂”吗？
Have you heard of "possession"'?
当然，坐下、躺下、蹲下……
Of course. Sitting, lying, squatting...
不是摄影，笨蛋，是“摄魂”
Not position, you fool. "Possession."
是什么鬼东西？
What the fuck is that?
摄取灵魂
Possessed by spirits.
拥有灵魂
Spirit possession.
在老家她非常出名
She's actually quite famous in her old town.
看到她如何抖动的吗？那是在做准备
Look how she's shaking? That's preparing.
准备干什么？
Preparing for what?
幽灵
Ghost.
她不穿袜子，因为每天早上她都在刀上行走
She doesn't weer socks because she walks on knife every morning.
不要用你的眼睛看她
Don't look her in the eyes.
你会被勾魂的
You'll get possessed.
对，好的
Yeah, right.
你知道吗，你总是像一个意大利面盘子？
Do you know you always look like a pasta plate?
你为什么不把头盔摘了？
Why don't you take off your helmet?
为什么你不先吐点乒乓球出来？
Why don't you spit out those ping pong balls first?
你的颧骨能杀人
Your cheekbones can kill people.
喔，你个疯婊子
Wow, you crazy bitch.
你嘴可真脏呀
You have a very filthy mouth.
不比你的脸更脏
Not more than your face.
你真是个奇女子呀
What a special haybag you are.
你更特殊
And you're extra special.
操你妈
You fucking mother fucker.
操你妈个傻逼
You fucking mother fucker sucker!
你个长角的狗，我要生吞了你
You horn dog, I'll eat you alive!
以牙还牙！
Right back atcha!
要是抖成这样，你走吧
Go away if you're gonna shake like that.
-你狗屎脸 -你狗屎脸
- You shitface. - You shitface.
基妮！我累了
Jinx! I'm getting bored.
-你…… -什么？
- You... - What?
-屎…… -屎蛋？
- Sh... - Shiznit?
你个狗屎笨蛋！
You skanky shiznit twat!
婊子！那是我要说的！
Bitch! That was mine!
操妈的婊子们
Fucking bitches.
你们这群吃舔猪油桶的傻逼！
You bunch of sap sucking lard buckets!
操他妈的臭嘴，满是鸡巴狗屎
Fuck that filthy mouth filled with whistledickin' shit.
别怪玩这场游戏的婊子
No blamin' the bitches for playin' the game.
那没什么，十八岁时你们都要生孩子
It doesn't matter. Y'all's gotta make babes when y'all's 18.
我得吃点东西，妈妈，我不能睡太晚了
I should've eaten somthing. Mom, I ain't gonna sleep late.
姥姥呼噜太响了，我再也睡不着了！
Granny snorin's too loud, I sleeped no more!
你个混蛋！
You peckerheads!
喔，是看MTV的时间了
Wow, it's already time to watch MTV.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
我正看着你
I'm just looking at you
我正观察着你
I'm just watching you
我从没说过我爱你
I can never say I love you
我只是看着你
I'm just looking at you
我应该做什么呢？
What should I do?
我只是转来转去
I just go round and round
我也想跟你姥姥上节私教
I want to get a private lesson from your granny too!
我感觉这么老！
I feel so old!
嗨，姑娘们！
Hey girls!
我想是时候接受我们的第七员了
I think it's time to accept our seventh member.
-谁？ -娜美
- Who? - Na-mi.
-七比六好 -好运气！
- Seven's better than six. - Lucky!
大家都同意接受娜美为我们的新成员吗？
Everybody agree to accept Na-mi as our new member?
-同意！ -支持！
- Agreed! - Seconded!
支持，夫人！
Positive, ma'am!
随便吧
Whatever.
现在我们七个人了，我们起个他妈的名字吧
Now that we're seven, let's make a fucking name.
-酷 -别骂了，疯婊子
- Cool. - Stop swearing, crazy bitch.
我喜欢“疯婊子”
I like "crazy bitch".
疯婊子？
Crazy Bitches?
嗨，“迷幻女孩”怎么样？
Hey, how's "Wonder Girls?"
喜欢“迷幻女孩”，无所谓
Like "Wonder Woman". Never mind.
那太没水平了
That's so cheesy.
-“疯婊子”就有创意了？ -吃这个
- And "Crazy Bitches" is creative? - Eat this.
哦，老天
Oh my god.
你吓死我了，小妹妹
You scare me, little sis.
-进来，我爸妈不在 -你好，江美
- Come in, my parents aren't here. - Hello, Jang-mi.
哇，江美
Wow, Jang-mi.
嗨，小可爱！
Hey cutie!
看起来很好，我的未来新娘子
Looking good, my future bride.
你要什么时间学习？你不想上大学了吗？
When are you gonna study? You don't want to go to college?
闭嘴，让开
Shut up and move.
秀智！还是依旧那么美丽！
Su-ji! Keep being pretty like that!
-当我上顶级大学…… -顶级大学？
- When I get into a top college... - Top college?
先去背背乘法表吧
Go memorize the multiplication tables first.
-我们有面条吗？ -自己做吧，你个猪头
- Do we have noodles? - Make it yourself, you hog.
-你要吃点面条吗？ -不加蛋
- Would you like some noodles? - Without egg.
你好，俊浩！
Hello, Jun-ho!
-嗨 -嗨！
- Hi. - Hi!
-很高兴见到你！ -他说“很高兴见到你！”
- Good to see you! - He said "good to see you!"
新面孔？
New face?
我们的新成员
Our newest member.
她很可爱
She's pretty.
-你听到了吗？ -一定是你他妈的过生日才有的好运气
- Did you hear that? - Must be your goddamn birthday.
谢谢你，江美
Thank you, Jang-mi.
-我要打你的脸 -回来，朋友！
- I'll smack you in the face. - Back atcha, girlfriend!
给我那个
Gimme that.
喔，就像画一样
Wow, it's a picture.
-你忘了眼皮了 -没有！
- You forgot the eyelid. - No!
这太美了
This is too pretty.
不是“potatoes”和“potatos”
It's not "potatoes," "potatos."
-是“potatoes” -对了
- It's "potatoes." - It's correct.
-闭嘴，笨蛋 -你打我？
- Shut up, idiot. - You hit me?
未来会有专业的视频游戏玩家
One day there will be pro video game player.
还有移动电话
And portable phones.
-不会很沉吗？ -会做成小的
- Wouldn't they be heavy? - They'll make small ones.
便携电脑！
And portable computers!
你可以在上面写信看无线广播
You'll write letters and watch radio shows on them.
看无线广播？
Watching radio shows?
当然，那是未来
Of course. It's future.
如果我能做那个，我就发财了
If I can make that, I'll be rich.
为什么，你应该说未来我们得买水喝
Why, you should say that we'll have to buy water in the future.
去你的屋子！
Go to your house!
为什么我们得买水？
Why would we buy water?
她说我们会有能拍照的手机！
She said we'll have phones that'll take pictures!
-开始了！ -听，听！
- It's on! - Listen, listen!
-我会记得我的朋友…… -姥姥！
- I'll remember my friends... - Granny!
春花、秀智、珍熙、江美、福姬和娜美
Chun-hwa, Su-ji, Jin-hee, Jang-mi, Bok-hee, and Na-mi.
如果你能给我们姐妹帮
If you could make a name
起个名字，我们将是好朋友
for our group, we will be good friends.
永远的
Forever.
金玉，阳光姐妹怎么样，“阳光姐妹？”
Geum-ok, how about S-U-N-N-Y, "Sunny?"
我希望你喜欢它
I hope you like it.
送一首歌给你们，正在度过
Here 's a song for you girls who are having the
生命中最好时光的姑娘们
best moments of your lives.
Jo Deok-bae的“在我梦中”
Jo Deok-bae's "In My Dream."
昨天我在梦中见到了你
Yesterday I saw you in my dream
我甚至不认识你
I don't even know you
但我忘不了你
but I can't forget you
或许我们曾相遇在某处
Maybe we've met somewhere
或许我已忘记
Maybe I've forgotten
但我已在某处遇见过你
But I've met you somewhere
我在深秋里遇见过你
I've met you in the fall
我害怕自己醒来
I'm afraid I'll wake up
从这个梦里……
from this dream...
想穿自己买呀
Buy your own.
嗨，江美
Hi, Jang-mi.
珍熙？脏话皇后？
Jin-hee? The swear queen?
现在的孩子太粗俗
Kids these days are so vulgar.
我们年轻的时候可不一样
We were different when we were young.
读书，听古典音乐……
Reading books and listening to classical music...
你过去一定是个有教养的孩子
You must have been such a cultured kid.
-对不起 -很是对不起
- I'm sorry. - I'm so sorry.
没问题，小心点
It's alright. Be careful.
你是珍熙？
Are you Jin-hee?
娜美？任娜美？
Na-mi? IM Na-mi?
你是江美？
And you're Jang-mi?
当然了
Of course.
对不起，我的声音太大了
Sorry, my voice was too big.
娜美，你一点都没变呀
Na-mi, you didn't change a bit.
江美，你……
And Jang-mi, you...
也一点没变
didn't change either.
你可变的太多了
You changed a lot.
除了嘴，你整个脸都变了
You changed your entire face except the mouth.
我没有！我是因为过敏才整了下鼻子
I did not! I did my nose because of allergies.
眼睛稍微整了一下
And tiny bit on the eye.
你来了，我的美人！
Here you are, my cutie pie!
我再来一场，你们玩好
Have a good time while I go for one more round.
你们是我老婆的好朋友吗？
Were you good friends with my wife?
对，我们在同一个学习小组
Yeah, we were in the same study group.
她在高中怎么样？受欢迎吧？
How was she in high school? Popular?
对，她非常……优雅
Yeah, she was very... elegant.
优雅的骂人家
Elegant curser.
无论什么时候要打架，她的嘴就是武器……
Whenever there was a fight, her mouth was a weapon...
我们谈些女人悄悄话，你该走了
Let us have girls' talk. You should go.
好的，好的，一会见
Ok, ok. I'll see you later.
可爱的松饼！
Cutie muffin!
江美，有什么不对吗？
Jang-mi, is there something wrong?
那你怎么样？你的孩子多大了？
So how are you? How old is your kid?
十七岁
Seventeen.
你隆胸了？现在都变成西瓜大了
You did your breasts? They're watermelons now!
太粗鲁了
That's so rude.
-娜美，你的丈夫做什…… -我们从未在一个学习组
- Na-mi, what does your husban... - We were never a study group.
操妈的狗屎！
Fuck this shit!
别这样，好吗？
Stop it, ok?
珍熙
Jin-hee.
你难道不想见春花吗？
Don't you wanna meet Chun-hwa?
我不敢相信你们通过侦探找到我
I can't believe you found me through a detective.
有什么不对吗？
What's wrong with that?
被陌生人跟踪感觉不好
It feels wrong to be followed by a stranger.
我们必须尽快找到你，那是唯一的方法
We had to find you fast and that was the only way.
你们应该也发现了其他的事情
You should've found something else.
你们有他们的名片吗？
Do you have their card?
要是他们有我的信息，我晚上睡不着觉
I can't sleep at night if they have my information.
日后再聊
Talk to you later then.
这能成
This will Work.
我找到另两个会通知你
I'll let you know when I find other two.
你能再多找一个人吗？
Can you find one more person, separately?
我只知道他的名字和年龄
I only know his name and age.
当然了……抱歉
Well of course... Excuse me.
哦，你还在这？
Oh, you're still here?
当然，我不会告诉任何人
Of course I won't tell anyone.
我会杀了你的！
I Will kill you!
给你！我认为你写错了车牌号
Here you are! I think you wrote the plate number wrong.
想知道他是否有婚外情，那是必须的
It's a necessity to find out if he's having an affair.
你在这干什么？
What are you doing here?
快点
Hurry up.
我走着呢
I'm going.
你不会告诉江美，是吗？
You're not gonna tell Jang-mi, right?
看看再说
We'll see.
-我这么做只是以防万一 -我说什么了吗？
- I'm doing it just in case. - Did I say anything?
谁呀？
Who is it?
我们来这布道的
We're here to spread the message from God.
我去过教堂了
I already go to church.
说这样更好
Say it nicer.
上帝爱你许多
God loves you a lot.
你们来自哪个教堂？
Which church are you from?
来喝点吧
Please have some.
房间很小，对吧？我们只在这短期居住
It's tiny, right? We're only staying for a while.
不，很不错
No, it's fine.
-很高兴见到你 -我明白
- Good to see you. - I know.
娜美，你看起来这么年轻
Na-mi, you look so young.
珍熙……
And Jin-hee...
我都认不出你了
I barely recognized you.
你在照看你的外甥吗？
Why are you babysitting your nephew?
我小姑子怀孕了，所以有段时间……
My sister-in-law is pregnant. So for a while...
金玉！
Geum-ok!
抱歉
Excuse me.
你难道不羞愧吗？你丈夫和小姑子
Aren't you ashamed? Your husband and sister-in-law
在辛苦的工作，但你却和朋友聊天
are doing all the hard work while you hang out with your friends.
招聘：老师和专家
WANTED: EDUCATORS & PROFESSIONALS
对不起
Sorry.
-来点咖啡 -好的
- Have some coffee. - Right.
你为什么把门关上？！
Why did you close the door?!
我说错了吗？
Did I say anything wrong?
天哪，她要把我关起来！
My god, she's locking me up!
孩子哭了，去抱她
Baby's crying. Go get him.
嗨，姐妹们
Hey guys.
你们能离开吗？
Can you please leave?
这不是她，不是我们认识的医生的女儿
That's not her. Not the denist's daughter we knew.
都是生活中该死的虚荣，是不是？
All is fucking vanity in life, isn't it?
现在你听起来像我的朋友了
Now you sound like my friend.
遇到你们这些姑娘后，我又一切如旧了
It's all coming back to me after meeting you girls.
嗨
Hey,
等等！
wait!
我没时间去看她
I can't find time to visit her.
你能代我把这个给她吗？
Can you give this to her for me?
求你了？
Please?
你难道不能来一小会吗？
Can't you stop by briefly?
如果我不呆在家，或许吧……
Perhaps if I didn't stay home...
我会给她打个电话，好吗？
I'll give her a call, OK?
我会再见到你们的，保重
And, I'll see guys again. Take care.
春花，对不起我不能去看你，金玉
CHUN-HWA, SORRY I COULDN'T GO SEE YOU. GEUM-OK.
给我亲爱的老婆
TO MY LOVING WIFE
我不吃饭了
I'm not eating.
-怎么了？ -没事
- What happened? - Nothing.
-你的脸有伤 -没事
- Your face is bruised! - It's nothing.
肯定有事，怎么了？
It's not nothing! What happened?
我摔了一跤！
I fell down!
艺彬，怎么了？发生什么事了？
Yae-bin, what's wrong? What happened?
青年明星音乐室
YOUNG STAR MUSIC ROOM
请进，耶！
Come on, yeah!
这里不接待中学生
Middle school kids are not allowed here.
我不是中学生
I'm not in middle school.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
来杯咖啡，黑的
Coffee please. Black.
先付钱
You pay first.
一千韩元
1000 won.
如果警察来了，后门在那边
Backdoor's that way if the cops come.
我们以前见过，是吗？你是江美的朋友
We saw before, right? You're Jang-mi's friend.
你喜欢音乐吗？你经常来这吗？
Do you like music? Do you come here often?
你紧张吗？
Do you have high pressure?
-低血糖…… -啊？什么？
- Diabetes... - Huh? What?
低血糖！
Diabetes!
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
厕所
Restroom.
洗一下手
To wash my hands.
操，操，该死，该死！
Fuck, fuck, shit, shit!
嗨！
Hey!
嗨
Hey.
好久没见了，摄魂大师
Long time no see, spirit master.
你们是谁？
Who are you?
难道春花没告诉你，这是我们的地盘？
Didn't Chun-hwa tell you this is our area?
-你妈…… -你个小烂货！
- You fuckin'... - You little fuck!
现在我什么都知道了！你个小骗子
I know everything now! You little liar.
我他妈的还真认为那是真的，婊子！
I fucking thought it was real, bitch!
该死的婊子
Damn bitch.
听说你们现在有名字了
Heard you guys have a name now.
阳光姐妹？
Sunny?
你给电台写信了？
You sent a letter to a radio?
我们也要把名字变成英文的
We're gonna change our name to English, too.
叫FINKLE
FINKLE.
借点钱给我们，我们好烫烫头
Lend us some money so we can go perm our hair.
-我没钱 -好呀！
- I don't have any. - Right!
该死的骗子
Damn liar.
搜她的身
Search her.
住手！住手！
Stop it! Stop!
按住她！
Hold her!
按住她的腿！
Hold her legs!
别盯着看！
Stop staring!
别那样看！
Stop staring like that!
我猜你没搞明白形势
I guess you don't realize the situation.
-没人会来…… -嗨！
- No one will come to... - Hey!
……来救你
...rescue you.
这真是预料之中了，你不觉着吗？
This is too predictable, don't you think?
我一有麻烦就来了
Come back when I'm the one in trouble.
新川女子职业高中？
Shinchang Girl's Vocational High?
对，那怎么了？
Yeah. So what?
你知道宋真玉吗？
You know SONG Jeong-ok?
脸上有二十公分疤的那人？
The one with a 20cm scar on her face?
我干的
I did that.
现在她还一喝东西就会从脸上溅出来
She still can't drink without spilling through her face.
该死
Bullshit.
把那个给我
Give me that.
我会给你们好看
I'll make yours pretty.
是看年轻十一的时候了
It's time to watch Young Eleven.
等等我们！
Wait for us!
你还好吗？
Are you ok?
现在的孩子为什么这么吓人？
Why are kids so scary these days?
我们走那边
Let's go that way.
如果我去参军，我想加入军乐队
If I go to the army, I want to join the military band.
你要参军吗？
Are you going to the army?
嗯，我不是非得去，我是三代单传
Nah, I don't have to. I'm the only son for three generations.
哦，好的
Oh, right.
我的名字是韩俊浩
My name's HAN Jun-ho.
我忘了介绍我……
I forgot to introduce my...
你的头发上有口香糖
There's a gum on your hair.
我认为是你被欺负时弄上的
I think it got on when you were being bullied.
你需要用丙酮才能除掉它
You'll need acetone to remove it.
又低血糖了？
Diabetes again?
我到了
I'm here.
我家在那
There's my house.
那么晚安
Good night then.
哦……
Oh and...
如果你再见到她们，告诉她们我是你的男朋友
if you meet them again, tell them I'm your boyfriend.
不，你不明白
No, you don't understand.
那个婊子勾引我儿子……
That bitch tempted my son to...
如果你看到你儿子，打电话给我们
If you see your son, call us.
制作传单册是严重的罪行
Making a propaganda leaflet is a serious felony.
你儿子会进监狱的
Your son could go to jail.
哦，该死！这是什么？！
Oh Shit! What's this?!
你妈的，进来吃晚饭
You motherfucker. Come in and eat dinner.
我觉着那太晚了
I think it's too late for that.
妈妈，请进去！
Mother, please go in!
别傻站着呀！
Do something!
-你要是有它，你会坐牢的 -送回去
- If you take it you go to jail. - Give it back!
-那么拿着它！ -妈妈！
- Take it then! - Mom!
拿着！
Take it!
如果你看见你儿子，立即给我们打电话，好吗？
If you see your son call us immediately, okay?
-对不起 -咱们走吧
- I'm so sorry. - Let's go.
这不是开玩笑
It's not a joke.
-对不起，我太对不起了 -该死，那真可怕
- Sorry, I'm so sorry. - Shit, that was scary.
对不起，我真对不起
Sorry, I'm so sorry.
为什么他碰到了这个疯女孩，开始搞工会运动？
Why did he meet this crazy girl and started labor movement?
他会成为我们大家的耻辱！
He's gonna shame us all!
下台！阴谋独裁者！
STEP DOWN! MURDEROUS DICTATOR!
下台，军政府！
Step down, military government!
学校没开，太好了，秀智啥时候来？
It's good that school's not on. When is Su-ji coming?
-她要成为明星 -美女们……
- She's gonna become a star. - Pretty girls...
那些烂货在哪？
Where are those hobags?
我没事的
It's really ok.
如果她们欺负我们中的一个，我们要一起报复
If they bully one of us, we pay back together.
大家好，我是瑞丽小姐，和平使者
Hello everyone. I'm Miss Ryu, the mascot of peace.
-停，笨蛋！ -身体三十四码大……
- Stop it, silly! - Body size 34...
该死，该死，该死……
Shit, Shit, Shit...
-竖起盾牌！ -竖起盾牌！
- Shield up! - Shield up!
下台，独裁者！我们需要自由！
Step down, dictator! We want freedom!
下台，军政府！
Step down, military government!
嗨，烂货！多么好的一天……
Hey hobags! What a great day to...
-狗屎样！ -狗屎样！基妮！
- Shitface! - Shitface! Jinx!
基妮你个狗屁没创意的笨蛋！
Jinx my ass you goddamn uncreative numskull!
狗血吃垃圾玩意！
Bloody barnacle biter!
闭上臭嘴，你们这些下三滥的笨蛋傻逼！
Screw your mouth from hell you pissy little nincompoop twat!
来舔我的袜子吧，大傻逼！
Come and suck my socks, skanky snatchin' windbag!
你个大毒逼！
You bloody druggie hoe!
呆子、傻瓜、笨蛋！
Nitwit ninny noodle!
- 以牙还牙！ - 以牙还牙，还牙！
- Right back atcha! - Right back and forth atcha!
-你过这来，婊子！ -别碰我的头发！
- Come here you bitch! - No touching my hair!
别碰！
No touching!
来呀！
Come here!
你看到过像这样的吗？
Have you seen anything like this?
你在看什么？
What ya lookin' at?
看你，笨蛋
At you, dummy.
我们去警局吧，我把一切都解释了
Let's go to the police. I've explained everything
我的儿子被坏人引诱了
that my good son was tempted by the wrong croud.
别说了，妈妈！没人引诱我干任何事情
Stop it, mom! Nobody tempted me into anything.
我和你一起，儿子
I'm coming with you, son.
-别傻了！ -炯哲！
- Don't be ridiculous! - Jong-gi!
炯哲？
Jong-gi?
我不在的时候照顾好姥姥
Take care of grandma while I'm gone.
好好表现，好吗？
And, be good. OK?
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
我决定献身于民主和劳动者权利
I decided to devote my life to democracy and workers' right.
你一定不要被物欲污染
You must never be tinged with bourgeois ideas.
带妈妈进去
Take mom inside.
经查被告有罪，故意不支付其雇员
The defendant was found guilty of deliberate failure to pay his employees,
汉斯和其他八名原告加班费
Hasan and 8 other plaintiffs, for a prolonged period of time.
本庭特此要求被告
The court hereby orders the defendant
立即支付所有拖欠工资
to immediately pay the entire amount of wage arrears
直到劳动合同终止
up to the termination of employment.
下一个，案件……
Next, case...
2000号……
number two thousand...
谢谢
Thank you.
炯哲
Jong-gi,
妈妈怎么样？
What about mom?
她在家，我给过她电话了
She's at home. I gave her a call.
你还好吗？
You okay?
不是你的生活方式，是吧？
Not the way to live your life, is it?
对不起，汉斯
I'm sorry, Hasan.
去死吧
Go to hell.
金玉给了我一千块钱
Geum-ok gave me a thousand bucks.
她做了朋友能做的事了
She did what she could for a friend.
你会穿不同的衣服，对吗？
You'll draw different clothes, right?
别动，我好久都没干这个了
Don't move. I haven't done this for a long time.
娜美
Na-mi.
嗯？
Yep?
你有想要做的事吗？
Is there something you want to do in life?
我太老了，没法有梦想了
I'm too old to have dreams.
不要没梦想地活着
Don't live without dreams.
人生苦短，无梦难活
Life is too short to live without them.
叫你别动了
Told you not to move.
春花……
Chun-hwa...
娜美……
Na-mi...
该死的混蛋有外遇
This fucking bastard is having an affair.
-谁？ -操！
- Who? - Fuck!
你打算怎么办？
What are you going to do?
对不起，春花
I'm sorry, Chun-hwa.
我真不想在我们重逢时说这些事情
I really didn't want to say stuff like this on our reunion.
别担心，我们都是朋友
Don't worry. We're all friends.
你也去搞外遇！
You go have an affair too!
谁想加入？
Who wants to join?
娜美？江美？
Na-mi? Jang-mi?
我还真有点想
I kinda want it.
但如果你也搞外遇，那你还能得到赡养费吗？
But if you do it, will you still get alimony?
该死，就是了
Shit, that's right.
我怎么才能报复这个该死的鸡巴玩意？
How am I going to pay back this whistle dick?
我们应该去一起报复吗？
Should we go and pay back together?
如果有人欺负我们中的一个，我们要一起报复，对吗？
If they bully one of us, we pay back together, right?
没错，娜美！
That's right, Na-mi!
你想怎么办呢？
How do you want it done?
像这样？
Like this?
或者像这样？！
Or like this?!
我什么都不怕，告诉我，我来办
I'm not scared of anything. Tell me and I'll do it.
那样不疼
It won't hurt like that.
你要像这样扭它，像这样！
You have to twist it like this. Like this!
别再折腾我老公的鸡巴了！
Stop mutilating my hubby's dick!
韩国姑娘总会在最后一刻保护老公
Korean girls always protect their husbands at the last moment.
你们这些婊子们，我的婊子们！
You bitches, my bitches!
你的电话无法接通……
Your call wasn't connected...
你为什么不接电话？
Why aren't you picking up the phone?
我会把车停在后面，打电话给我
I'll park at the back. Call me.
为什么你没有？
Why do you not have it?
-你疯了吗？ -妈的滚蛋！
- Are you nuts? - Fuck off!
-带钱给我，好吗？ -嗨！
- Bring me money, ok? - Hey!
艺彬，你还好吗？
Yae-bin, are you ok?
你们为什么这么做？过来呀！
Why did you do this? Come here!
-操…… -你为什么这么做？
- The fuck... - Why are you doing this?
她们是谁？
Who are they?
你关心什么？
What do you care?
这是怎么回事？她们是谁？
What's this? Who are they?
如果我告诉你她们是谁，你要做什么？
If I tell you who they are, what can you do?
杀了她们？
Kill them?
你就别管了
Just go away.
艺彬！
Yae-bin!
嗨，保险女
Hey, insurance lady.
像你这样的高贵要人在这做什么？
What's a noble personage like you doing here?
今天是流血的好日子
It's a good day to shed blood.
你穿的很不合适呀
You're dressed inappropriately
闭嘴！我们用老方法解决
Shut up! We'll do it the old way.
怎么办？
How?
我要骂死她们
I'll forstall them with my words.
这才是我的姐妹！
That's my girl!
顺便问一句，这些不是真的，是吗？
By the way, those aren't real, are they?
闭上你的臭嘴！
Shut your pie hole!
另外，其他人在哪？
Anyway, where are the others?
妈的怎么回事？
What the fuck?
我觉着她们可能认出我
Thought they might recognize me.
粗人！你老公很幸运
Saucy! Your husband is a lucky guy.
嗨，我的婊子们！
Hello, my bitches!
天那，你要笑死我呀！
God, you're killing me!
看看你！
Look at you!
你真是一个好学妹
You're a goddamn schoolgirl.
但相当可爱，你还真像呀
Kinda cute, though. You can still pull it off.
她说她累了，另外，我们不能不带领队呀
She said she was bored. Besides, we can't leave out the leader.
当然
Sure.
她整好奶子了
She got her boobs done.
-别搞笑了！ -那么咋样？
- No kidding! - So what?
-让我看看 -姐妹们，是她们！
- Let me see. - Guys, it's them!
-是她们？ -待在后面，春花
- That's them? - Stay in the back, Chun-hwa.
丢掉癌症患者不能打架的偏见吧
Lose the prejudice that cancer patients can't fight.
表演时刻到了
It's show time.
这是无烟区，婊子们！
It's a non-smoking area, bitches!
-你妈个逼的！ -操！
- You fucking motherfucker! - Fuck!
-你个狗屎笨蛋！ -STFU!
- You skanky shiznit twat! - STFU!
这个婊子到底在说什么？
What the hell is this bitch saying?
我只是来洗车，有人打电话给我
I just came to wash the car and got called.
我认为她们没疯，但有一个穿着校服
I don't think they're crazy, but one's wearing a uniform.
或许是COSPLAY
Maybe it's a costume play.
不管怎么说，我一会到那
Anyways, I'll be there soon.
牌子包真是很棒
Designer bags are awesome.
打破了脑袋了吧
Cracks open the brain at once.
好玩吗？
Is it funny?
警官，这不在保险理赔范围内，是吧？
Officer, this doesn't get covered by insurance, right?
你怎么能有这种奢望？这是暴力行为
How can you expect that? This is an act of violence.
有些保险含伤害……
Some insurance can cover injuries...
你有保险吗？
Do you have insurance?
在这种情况下你怎么还能做生意呢？
How can you do your business in this situation?
如果我再业绩很差，这个月我就出局了
If I perform poorly again, I'm out this month.
你应该买些，你有钱
You should buy some. You're rich.
你看到她今天的飞舞了吗？
Did you see her fly today?
她有铁拳！
She's got some iron fists!
复仇和公正
Revenge and justice.
有人需要帮助吗？
Anyone else need our help?
我们应该做这个生意
We should start a business in this.
咱们做校服吧！
Let's make uniforms!
学校的校服真是相当舒服
This school uniform's actually quite comfy.
我们也印传单！
Let's make flyers, too!
最小的费用，最大的满足
Minimum fee, maximum satisfaction
-“阳光姐妹回来了！” -阳光姐妹！
- "Sunny is back!" - Sunny!
安静！
Be quiet!
-警官 -啥事？
- Officer. - What?
你能把声音调大点吗？
Can you turn up the volume?
嗯？好
Yeah? Right.
开打！
Attack!
娜美跳舞很屎，她能过得了庆典吗？
Na-mi sucks at dancing. Will she survive at the festival?
该死！来上我呀！
Dang! I really suck my ass!
那让这笨蛋滚蛋
Then get the fuck out.
没有笨蛋，我们会更好
We're better off without a clown.
嗨！
Hey!
那太刻薄了
That was bit mean.
春花，你爱她吗？
Chun-hwa, do you love her?
-你是女同吗？ -什么？
- Are you a lesbian? - What?
你和女的怎么干？
How do you do it with a woman?
阳光姐妹还是狗屎姐妹，我不再关心了
Sunny or shitty, I don't care any more.
我要离开这
I'm out of here.
你想干什么？
What do you want?
我不理解你为什么恨我？
I don't understand why you hate me.
但我不能让你那样离开我们
But I can't let you leave us like that.
-我们？ -对，我们！
- Us? - Yes, us!
你长胆了，什么时候我们这么亲了？
You've grown ballsy. When were we ever "us?"
我想知道你为什么恨我
I want to know why you hate me.
没理由，我就是恨你的一切
There's no reason. I just hate your everything.
失陪了
Get lost.
你那也不能去！
You're not going anywhere!
放开
Get off.
你是秀智的朋友吗？
Are you Su-ji's friend?
晚安
Good evening.
很高兴见到你，你吃饭了吗？
Nice meetin' ya. Have ya eaten yet?
滚开
Fuck off.
她从未带过朋友，来和我们吃点东西吧
She never brings a friend. Come eat somethin' with us.
我已经吃了
I ate somethin' already.
你也是来自全罗道的吗？
You from Jeolla-do too?
我说滚开
I said fuck off.
带她进来，妈妈要做些东西……
Bring her in, Mommy'll make something...
谁说你是我妈妈？你是继母！
Who says you're my mom? You're a stepmom!
晚安！
Good night!
你恨我是不公平的，就因为
It's not fair to hate me because
你的继母来自全罗道
your stelomom's from Jeolla-do.
那是违背……
That's against...
民主主义的，并且它鼓励了地区……
democracy and it encourages regional...
你甚至不能喝酒？
You can't even drink alcohol?
我活的也不容易，我哥哥是个民主分子
It's hard for me too. My brother's a democratic activist.
他应该坐牢去
He might go to jail.
我姥姥叫我“姐妹”
And my granny calls me "sis".
我要说的是“我们”是重要的
What I'm sayin' is that "us" is important.
你知道为什么“我们”是重要的？
You know why "us" is important?
但……我不喜欢你
Still... I don't like you.
但我仍旧喜欢你
But I still like you.
为什么？
Why?
因为你很漂亮
Cuz you're pretty.
坦白地讲，看到你我很震惊
Honestly, I was so shocked when I saw you.
在我过去的学校，我真的是最漂亮的
I was actually the prettiest in my old school.
但在首尔，所有的姑娘都漂亮
But in Seoul all the girls are pretty.
但你是最漂亮的
But you're the prettiest.
我喜欢你，你是世界上最漂亮的姑娘
I like you. You're the prettiest girl in the world!
对不起我这么漂亮，都是我的错
I'm sorry that I'm so pretty. It's all my fault.
你说什么呢？我才是该说对不起的人
What are you saying? I'm the one who's sorry.
我将不再这么漂亮，你现在很漂亮了
I'll stop being so pretty. You can be pretty now.
我也漂亮，对不起
I'm pretty, too. I'm sorry.
我会为你变成一个首尔姑娘
I'll become a Seoul girl for you.
等等，让我多喝点
Wait, let me drink more.
请再来杯烧酒！
One more soju please!
福姬成为韩国小姐了吗？
Did Bok-hee become a Miss Korea?
我们快点去吧
Let's go soon.
对，我想她
Yeah, I miss her.
不，我要去看春花，我有东西给她
No, I'm seeing Chun-hwa. I've something to give her.
我应该问一下她是否明天想来吗？
Should I ask if she wants to come tomorrow?
好的
Ok.
帮我……
Help me...
她母亲贷款来保住美发厅
Her mom took out loans to save her salon.
但她还不起钱，所以她开始在酒吧工作……
But she couldn't pay back, so she started working at bars...
……最后到的这
...and ended up here.
-她女儿怎样？ -她在救济院
- What about her daughter? - She's in a facility.
可怜的福姬……
Poor Bok-hee...
我们走吧
Let's just go.
我不能再看这个了
I can't see this any more.
朋友就是共患难的
Friends are for hard times.
福姬
Bok-hee.
对不起，我太喜欢咖啡了
Sorry. I like coffee too much.
我们去看春花吧，我们要马上离开吗？
Let's go see Chun-hwa. Shall we leave right now?
我可以先离开，我也是先离开学校的
I can leave early. I left school early, too.
如果你没带男的来，你就没有自由时间
If you don't bring a guy, you don't get a free time.
如果你没其他的事做，去打扫厕所！
If you have nothing else to do, go clean the toilet!
对不起，她平时挺好的
Sorry. She's usually nice.
我马上回来，喝你们的咖啡吧
I'll be back soon. Drink your coffee.
对不起，夫人
I'm so sorry, ma'am.
-对不起 -闭嘴！
- I'm sorry. - Shut up!
嗨！
Hey!
给我这最贵的酒
Give me the most expensive bottle here.
能再说一遍吗？
Pardon me?
最贵的、标价最高的
The most expensive and overpriced one.
再把最贵的食物拿这来
Also bring the most expensive food here.
我会为她付费的，今天你服务
And I'll pay for her fee. You serve today.
一百万韩元够了吗？想要更多也成
Is one million won enough? I'll pay more if you want.
给
Here.
坐这里
Sit here.
你是我的英雄，娜美！
You're my hero, Na-mi!
拿真的酒来，不是假货！
Bring real liquor, not the fake one!
好的
Alright.
福姬，我们给你找其他的工作
Bok-hee, let's find you another job.
为什么？我不需要，你想要傻逼吗？
Why? I don't need to. Do you want beef jerky?
我会帮你找其他的工作
I'll help you find other job.
但我什么也不会
But I don't have any skills.
我能做点美发工作，记得我妈妈的美发厅吗？
I can do some hairdreesing. Remember my mom's hair salon?
我给过你们所有人双眼皮贴，对吗？
I gave you all the double eyelid tapes, right?
对，让我们做些那样的事吧
Yes, let's do something like that.
你有个女儿，你必须和她一起生活
You have a daughter. You have to live with her.
我想和宝美一起生活
I want to live with Bo-mi.
没有我，她甚至不能……
Without me, she can't even...
……打开热水器 -福姬
...turn on the heater... - Bok-hee.
我们会帮你的
We'll help you.
你们怎么帮我？
How can you help me?
为什么春花要死？
And why is Chun-hwa dying?
难道她不想照顾我们大家了吗？嗯？
Isn't she supposed to take care of us all? Huh?
娜美
Na-mi.
为什么你……只是看着？
Why are you... just looking?
你没在睡觉吗？
You weren't sleeping?
过来
Come here.
-春花 -怎么了？
- Chun-hwa. - What?
谢谢你
Thank you.
为什么？
For What?
长时间以来，我是作为一个妻子和某个人的母亲生活……
For a long time, I lived as a wife and a mother of someone...
都忘了我过去是什么样的了
and forgot how I was my own being.
现在我意识到我是自己生活的主宰
Now I realize that I'm the protagonist of my life.
你有一张主宰者的脸
You have a face of a protagonist.
秀智也有一张主宰者的脸……
Su-ji also had a face of a protagonist...
我们会为你找到她
I'll find her for you.
这是什么？
What's this?
阳光姐妹
SUNNY
丈夫
HUSBAND
娜美！拿住了它
Na-mi! Hold it straight.
春花
Chun-hwa
在男人的世界里，你干得很棒
you've done a great job in a man 's world.
我不能相信，你仍旧照顾这些家伙！
I can't believe you're still taking care of these guys!
我认为你是最棒的
I think you're the best.
江美，我认为你会是最棒的整形病人
Jang-mi, I think you'll be the best plastic surgery patient.
做了双眼皮后，你变得如此美丽
You'll turn so beautiful after the double eyelid surgery.
珍熙！我知道你会编一部脏话字典，并且
Jin - hee! I know you'll make a swearword dictionary and
和某个男子坠入爱河……操！
with a man you fall in love... Fuck!
你要和男人做什么……？
You're gonna do what with a man...?
我想当笨蛋！
I wanna do it foo!
你好，金玉！我知道你会变成著名的作家
Hello Geum-ok! I know you'll become a very famous writer.
我也读过你的书，非常棒……
I also read your book and it was awesome...
福姬！
Bok-hee!
嗨，福姬，我相信你现在是韩国小姐了
Hi, Bok-hee. I believe you're a Miss Korea by now.
你可能有了爱你的丈夫和孩子
And you probably have a loving husband and children.
太棒了！
That's so awesome!
福姬，人人都会爱你的
Bok-hee, you'll be loved by everyone.
我非常爱你！
I love you so much!
-秀智！ -我们的杂志模特！
- Su-ji! - Our magazine model!
-给我们摆个姿势！ -对了，给我们看看！
- Show us some pose! - Yeah, show us!
-给我们看看！ -给我们看看！
- Show us! - Show us!
该你了，娜美
It's your turn, Na-mi.
你好，未来的娜美
Hello, Na-mi of the future.
我是高中的娜美
I'm the high school Na-mi.
我认为你现在是艺术家了
I think you'd be an artist by now.
你一上大学就成了DJ
And once you're in college you'd be a DJ.
我也想成为漫画书店老板
And I also want to become an owner of a comic bookstore.
我不会收取过期费，并且……
I won't charge late fee. Also...
我认为你看起来真像苏菲.玛索
I think you really look like Sophie Marceau.
什么？
What?
我将会出演初吻这样的电影
I'll be in movies like La Boum.
并且我也想成为舞蹈家……
And I also wanna become a dancer...
你甚至不会跳舞！
You can't even dance!
春花，过来！
Chun-hwa, come here!
你要去哪？
Where're you going?
喝水去！
To drink water!
给我买个沙拉面包！
Buy me a salad bun!
没钱！
No money!
嗨，村姑！
Hey, farm girl!
你喝水像个真的村姑一样
You drink water like a true farm girl.
你想要干什么？
What do you want?
我有话要问
I have something to ask.
我听说在农村……
I heard that in the countryside...
……人们在草垛后群交
...people group fuck behind hay stacks.
-你干过吗？ -李相美！
- Have you done that? - LEE Sang-mi!
闭上臭嘴！
Shut the fuck up!
哇，吓死我了
Wow, I'm impressed.
别期望春花和她的姐妹一直黏在一起
Don't expect Chun-hwa and her pals to stick around forever.
-她们会踹掉你，只要…… -别他妈的和我瞎扯！
- They'll dump you as soon as... - Stop fucking with me!
这次我让你走
I'm letting you go this once.
小心点！
Be careful!
在垃圾堆见
MEET ME AT THE GARBAGE DUMP.
嗨，村姑！
Hey, farm girl!
你没说我必须独自前来
You didn't say I have to come alone.
说对不起
Say sorry.
什么？
What?
如果你说对不起，我会原谅这一切
If you say sorry, I'll forgive everything.
我不说
I won't.
那么我先说，我对不起说脏话了
I'll say it first, then. I'm sorry I used swearwords.
我听说你和春花是朋友，但你们打过架
I heard you were friends with Chun-hwa but you had a fight
因为春花不喜欢你臭烘烘的……
because Chun-hwa didn't like you sniffing glue...
我再也不能听这些屁话了
I can't listen to this bullshit any more.
你们这些家伙叫自己什么？阳光姐妹？
You guys call yourself what? Sunny?
你们没有意识到这是你们的末日
You guys don't realize this is the end of yours.
我要把你们都杀了，一个接一个……
I'm going to kill all of you, one by one...
……就从今天开始
...starting from today.
给我相机
Give me the camera.
把衣服脱了
Take them off.
真妈的乱呀！
What a fucking mess.
再说一遍，你想做什么？
Say that again. You're gonna do what?
妈的婊子！
Fucking bitch!
你想要你那美丽的脸毁掉吗？
Do you want your pretty face to get ruined?
我会抓花你的……
I'll scratch your...
你得带她去医院了
You'll have to take her to the hospital.
别那么干，秀智！
Don't do it, Su-ji!
别那么干！
Don't do it!
如果我是你
If I were you
我会感到太羞耻而不去学校
I'd be too shamed to come to school.
我们打算和哥哥的朋友出去旅行
We're going on a travel with my bro's friends.
两天，你应该加入
Two days. You should join.
俊浩也要过来！
Jun-ho is coming too!
发生什么事了？
What happened?
天哪，有什么不对吗？
Gosh, what's wrong?
你打架了？
Did you fight?
-我摔跤了 -你没有
- I fell down. - You did not!
相当严重
It's quite serious.
谁他妈的在学校抽烟？
Who the fuck smokes in school?
美国香烟？
And American cigarette?
我难道没告诉你们，如果我发现你们抽烟，我会撕了你们吗？
Didn't I tell you I'll rip you off if I find you smoking?
把你们包里和口袋里的所有东西放到桌子上
Put everything in your bag and pocket on the desk.
现在！
Now!
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
站起来
Get up.
站起来，站起来！
Get up. Get up!
你不站起来？嗯？站起来！
You're not getting up? Huh? Get up!
妈的站起来！
Get the fuck up!
好，你死定了
Ok. You're a dead meat.
你让我真生气了
You're making me real angry.
我让你见识一下海军陆战队员怎么打你这样的婊子的
I'll show you how a Marine beats bitches like you.
回军队去，干你自己吧，妈个逼的！
Go back to the army and fuck yourself, motherfucker!
我们仍旧找不到郑秀智
We still can't find JUNG Su-ji.
这不是最好的解决方法，但我们会发讣告
This isn't the best solution, but we could publish an obituary.
但当然，我们会再次尝试的
But of course, we'll try again.
你要我单独找的那个人……
And the person you asked me to find separately...
韩俊浩
HAN JUN-HO
没我别打她！
Don't hit her without me!
有事吗？
Wassup?
没事
Nothing.
来和我们玩吧
Come and play with us.
请进！
Come on in!
-请来咖啡 -好的
- Coffee, please. - Sure.
爸爸！你晚了
Dad! You're late.
你很长时间没来这了
You haven't been here for a long time.
没有吗？
No?
有一段时间了
It's been a while.
我终于把这个给你了
I can finally give this to you.
真德校庆
JINDEOK SCHOOL FESTIVAL
我爱秀智
I LOVE SU-JI
秀智是我的生命
SU-JI IS MY LIFE
媒体的力量呀！
The power of mass media!
在秀智上了杂志后，她的粉丝翻了三番！
After Su-ji got on the magazine, her fans have tripled!
她要是变成了真的电影明星怎么办？
What if she becomes a real movie star?
没啥大不了的
Not a big deal.
要是你变成了电影明星，我们把双眼皮手术也一起做了！
If you become a movie star, let's do the eyelid surgery together!
我会为你做的！
I was gonna do that for you!
你为什么行为怪怪的？
Why are you acting weird?
没事
Nothing.
去弄点东西吃吧，我们时间充足
Go get something to eat. We have enough time.
娜美！
Na-mi!
我太想你了
I thought of you a lot.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我应该对新人更好点
I should have been nicer to a new kid.
原谅我
Forgive me.
不，我对不起
No, I'm sorry.
真的？
Really?
那么我们一起吃饭来庆祝我们的友谊
Then let's eat together to celebrate our friendship.
你闻起来臭烘烘的
You smell like glue.
我闻起来？
I smell?
我闻起来吗？！
Do I smell?!
不是
No.
-你闻起来臭烘烘的…… -妈的别闹了！
- You smell like glue... - For fuck's sake!
当然我闻起来！
Of course I smell!
你喝的是“阳光十号”，所以你闻起来像阳光
You drink "Sunny 10", so you smell like Sunny.
你想要些吗？
You want some?
你应该试试，来吧
You should try it. Come on.
来吧
Come on.
继续，喝
Go on, drink.
继续！
Go on!
下面使我们自豪的太鼓象皮乐队
Next is our proud drum and fife band,
她们在非洲成功巡演后回来
who came back from the successful Africa tour!
哦，性感
Ooh, sexy
春花
Chun-hwa.
我给你买这个
I'm buying you this.
你应该喝点东西
You gotta drink something.
好的
That's ok.
为什么？你认为我脏吗？
Why? You think I'm dirty?
为我们的友谊干杯！
Drink it for our friendship!
从现在起我就是阳光姐妹了，阳光的味道，阳光……
I'm Sunny from now on. Sunny smell, Sunny...
我告诉你如果你是来恶心人的，我会杀了你的！
I told you I'll kill you if you come sniffin' glue!
拉她起来
Get her up.
为什么我不被允许？
Why am I not allowed?
她有什么特殊的？
What's so special about her?
嗨，漂亮脸蛋
Hey, pretty face.
- 秀智！ - 秀智！
- Su-ji! - Su-ji!
从这出去！
Get out of here!
秀智……
Su-ji...
你们都被退学了
You're all expelled.
在领导面前干的不错呀！
Fantastic job in front of the inspector!
另一个在哪？嗨，你！
Where is the other one? Hey, you!
来这，小狗屎！
Come here, little piece of shit!
来这！
Come here!
过去的学校就是这么教你的吗？
Is that how you were taught in your old school?
我变卖一切搬到这里，为了你的教育！
I sold everything to move here. For your education!
别打她！
Don't hit her!
一个去坐牢，另一个被停学
One goes of jail, the other gets suspended!
滚出我的房子，你们都滚！
Get the fuck out of my house. All of you!
你为什么……
Why did you hang out...
-……和坏女孩混在一起？ -请别打她，爸爸
...with bad girls? - Please don't hit her, papa.
父亲
Father.
我出卖了我的战友来保全自己
I sold out my comrades to save my skin.
我是该死的狗
I'm a goddamn dog.
从现在起我将像狗一样生活
I'll live like a dog from now.
哦，我的宝贝，我的儿子！
Oh, my baby. My son!
我的孩子！
My boy!
她怎么样了？
How is she?
她试图自杀
She tried to kill herself.
没事，她没死
It's ok. She's not dead.
没事
It's ok.
我们不打算彼此再见了吗？
We're not going to see each other again?
任娜美！
IM Na-mi!
被赶出学校不是阳光姐妹的结束
Getting expelled from school isn't the end of Sunny.
我们会再见的，带秀智和我们一起
We'll meet again, bring Su-ji with us
跳我们今天不能跳的舞
and dance what we couldn't dance today.
明白吗？
Understand?
你们明白吗？
Do you understand?
我们会再见的
We'll meet again.
如果你因为你的生活太好而忽略我们
If you ignore us because your life is too good,
我们会去惩罚你的
we'll go and punish you.
如果你因为生活不如意而躲着
If you hide because your life sucks,
我们会去让它变好点
we'll go and make it better.
我不知道我们中谁会先死
I don't know who will die first among us,
但直到那一天……
but until that day...
不，甚至是过了那一天……我们，阳光姐妹，绝不会分开
No, even beyond that day... We, Sunny, will never break up.
-你为什么来？ -我想你
- Why did you come? - I missed you.
一切还好吗？
Everything okay?
是的，一切还好
Yeah, everything's ok.
市中心通常是最好的路线……
Downtown is usually the best route...
-冯先生？ -是？
- Mr. Bong? - Yes?
市中心从来就不是最好的路线
Downtown is never the best route.
好的……
Ok...
咋啦？
What?
什么？
妈妈！
Mom!
你的电话
Your phone.
江美？
Jang-mi?
这就是独身死去的问题，没有家庭
This is the problem of dying single. No family.
那就是为什么你不会离婚吗？
Is that why you won't get a divorce?
他给了我一栋楼
He gave me a building.
而且他说他再也不会了
Also he said he won't again.
你现在也有婚外情了吗？
Did you have an affair too?
你有吗？
You did?
你有！
You did!
你说过我们应该一起干的！
You said we should do it together!
谁说我有？
Who said I did?
你说过你会考虑一下的，你个优柔寡断的婊子
And you said you'd think about it, you indecisive bitch.
葬礼的时候别骂人
Stop swearing in the funeral.
疯婊子
Crazy bitches.
娜美
Na-mi.
金玉？
Geum-ok?
你怎么做到的？
How did you make it?
我不再在乎了
I don't care any more.
你真棒，姑娘！
You go girl!
金玉，医生的女儿！
Geum-ok the dentist's girl!
好久不见！
Long time no see!
-你过的怎么样？ -很好
- How have you been? - Good.
你一点没变
You haven't changed a bit.
-是吗？ -对
- Really? - Yeah.
见到你真高兴！
It's so nice to see you!
等一下，我想和春花打个招呼
Wait a sec, I want to say hi to Chun-hwa.
你可以等等，大家都到齐了我们再一起去
You can wait. We'll do it together when everybody comes.
还有谁要来？秀智吗？她还好吗？
Who else is coming? Su-ji? Is she ok?
福姬怎么样？她变成韩国小姐了吗？
What about Bok-hee? Did she become a Miss Korea?
奖金太少了
The prize money was too small.
很高兴见到你们！
It's good to see you guys!
为什么没人来这？
How come nobody's here?
真正的葬礼是昨天
The actual funeral was yesterday.
今天她只想见我们
Today she just wanted us.
春花总是特殊，让我们等秀智一起吧
Chun-hwa's always special. Let's wait for Su-ji together.
秀智要来吗？她的脸还好吗？
Su-ji is coming? Is her face ok?
我们没有真正找到她，但我们打了广告了
We didn't actually find her, but we did put an ad.
秀智，请参加春花的最后演唱会！
SU-JI, PLEASE ATTEND CHUN-HWA'S LAST CONCERT!
我们坐下里聊聊吧
Let's sit down and talk.
我们等到十二点吧，大家觉着成吗？
Let's wait till 12. Everybody ok with that?
金玉？
Geum-ok?
我没问题，今晚不回那去了
I'm fine. Not going back there tonight.
福姬，你怎么样？
Bok-hee, what do you do?
那个什么……我正在找新工作
This and that... I'm looking for a new job.
你很幸运，每个女人都应有个工作
You're so lucky. Every women should have a job.
我厌倦被我丈夫和他家人忽略了
I'm tired of being ignored by my husband and his family.
我认为有个丈夫不是坏事
I don't think it's a bad thing to have a husband.
-什么？他们欺负你？ -嗯
- What? Do they bully you? - Uh-huh.
-我们应该惩罚他们吗？ -对！
- Should we punish them? - Yeah!
难道我没告诉你，我们打了欺负娜美女儿的人吗？
Didn't I tell you about when we beat up Na-mi's daughter's bully?
-没，从没有！ -告诉我，告诉我！
- No, never! - Tell me, tell me!
有点复杂……
It's a bit complicated...
我猜秀智不会来了
I guess Su-ji can't make it.
-我们现在应该行礼了吗？ -好的
- Should we greet now? - Alright.
你是来参加夏春花的葬礼的吗？
Did you come for HA Chun-hwa's funeral?
我是夏女士的律师
I'm the lawyer of Mrs. HA.
你是“阳光姐妹”的成员吗？
Are you the members of "Sunny?"
我来这是执行夏女士的遗嘱的
I'm here to execute the will of Mrs. HA.
她特别嘱咐我要生动地读出来
She especially ordered me to read it realistically.
所以请忍着点我
So please bear with me.
嗨，婊子们！
Hey bitches!
我只是读得像……
I just read it like...
对不起，我接着读
Sorry, I'll read it again.
嗨，婊……婊……我略过这些
Hey b... b... I'll skip that.
大家都在着吗？
Is everyone here?
如果你没来，我理解
If you didn't make it, I understand.
对不起，我们未能履行我们的誓言
I'm sorry we didn't keep the promise we made
二十五年前在秀智的房前所发的誓言
in front of Su-ji's house 25 years ago.
我知道死的这么早，我是个坏领队
I know I'm a bad leader for dying so early.
娜美，谢谢找到我们的朋友
Na-mi, thanks for finding our friends.
我的生命不长，但是……
My life wasn't long, but...
如你所说，我是自己生命的主宰
as you've said, I was the protagonist of my life.
为此谢谢你
Thank you for that.
娜美将是阳光姐妹的下一个领队
Na-mi will be the next leader of Sunny.
请为我享受生命
Please enjoy the life together for me,
你们大家都是
all of you.
保重
Take care.
恭喜你，娜美
Congrats, Na-mi.
谢谢
Thanks.
夏女士留了礼物给你们大家
Mrs. HA left presents for all of you.
金江美
KIM Jang-mi.
是？
Yes?
你是一个保险代理吗？
Are you an insurance agent?
对
Yes.
这的每个人都要买你卖的每份保险
Everyone here is going to buy every insurance you sell.
所有的费用将全额支付
All the fees will be paid in full.
我真为你高兴！
I'm so happy for you!
怎么……？
How...?
她留下了大量的钱
She left a large sum of money behind.
她把剩余的捐给慈善组织，另外……
She donated the rest to charity and...
你是本月的保险皇后了，婊子！
You're the insurance queen of the month, bitch!
我以前还从未当过皇后！
I've never been a queen before!
黄珍熙
HWANG Jin-hee.
是？
Yes?
你可以是副领队
You can be the vice-leader.
就这样
That's it.
但我过去总是副领队
But I was always the vice-leader.
别说瞎话了，副领队是我
Don't lie. The vice-leader was me.
你在说什么呀？
What are you talking about?
秀智和我过去一直是副领队
Su-ji and I were always the vice-leader.
你失望吗？
Are you disappointed?
不完全如此……
Not exactly...
她告诉我如果你失望，就读这里
She told me to read here if you're disappointed.
我没有
I'm not.
说什么？
What does it say?
婊子！你有钱了！
Bitch! You're rich!
你有钱了！
You are rich!
-你甚至有栋楼房！ -好的，好的
- You even have a building! - Okay, okay.
-徐金玉 -是?
- SEO Geum-ok. - Yes?
你主修韩国文学吗？
You majored in Korean Literature?
对，是的
Yes I did.
在夏女士名下有个小出版公司
There's a small publishing company under Mrs. HA.
你会在那开始实习
You'll start there as an intern,
六个月后正式聘用
hired after six months,
如果你能维持150%的销售率两年
and if you maintain the 150% sales rate for two years,
你会被聘为总经理
you'll be hired as the executive manager.
真的吗？
Really?
-对你太好了！ -祝贺你！
- Good for you! - Congrats!
她也留下了这些话
She also left these words.
如果你搞糟了，我会杀了你的
I'll kill you if you screw up.
春花就是那样！
That's so Chun-hwa!
金福姬
RYU Bok-hee.
是
Yes.
她留给了一个公寓给你，让你和你女儿一起住
She left you an apartment to live with your daughter.
所有的生活费用、学费和结婚费用
All the living expenses, tuition, and marriage expenses
将由公司基金提供
will be provided by the company fund.
她也为你预定了康复医院
She also booked a hospital for your rehab.
当你变得更好后，你将接受职业培训
When you get better, you'll go through a vocational training
在金玉公司的一层
and open up your own business on the 1st floor
开创你自己的事业
of Geum-ok's company.
谢谢！
Thank you!
-谢谢！ -福姬……
- Thank you! - Bok-hee...
有件事你们必须做
There's one thing you need to do.
你们都收到了挂号信了吗？
Did all of you receive registered mail?
跳舞录像
The dance video.
这是春花的最后愿望，我们要完美实现
This is Chun-hwa's last wish. Let's make it awesome.
你练过了吗？
Did you practice?
我为减肥试过几次
I tried few times for diet.
葬礼上允许我们这么做吗？
Are we allowed to do this in a funeral?
领队想这样
The leader wants it.
如果有人抱怨，我负责
If someone complains, I'll take the responsibility.
你是领队！
You the leader!
副领队支持你！
The vice-leader's got your back!
好，咱们跳吧！
Ok. Let's do this!